<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ShortStoryApp</string>

    <string name="story_1_name">"
The Little Gingerbread Man"
</string>
    <string name="story_1_description">Once upon a time there was an old woman who loved baking gingerbread. She would bake gingerbread cookies, cakes, houses and gingerbread people, all decorated with chocolate and peppermint, caramel candies and colored frosting.
</string>
    <string name="story_1_content">"Once upon a time there was an old woman who loved baking gingerbread. She would bake gingerbread cookies, cakes, houses and gingerbread people, all decorated with chocolate and peppermint, caramel candies and colored frosting.

She lived with her husband on a farm at the edge of town. The sweet spicy smell of gingerbread brought children skipping and running to see what would be offered that day.

Unfortunately the children gobbled up the treats so fast that the old woman had a hard time keeping her supply of flour and spices to continue making the batches of gingerbread. Sometimes she suspected little hands of having reached through her kitchen window because gingerbread pieces and cookies would disappear. One time a whole gingerbread house vanished mysteriously. She told her husband, ""Those naughty children are at it again. They don't understand all they have to do is knock on the door and I'll give them my gingerbread treats.""
One day she made a special batch of gingerbread men because they were extra big. Unfortunately for the last gingerbread man she ran out of batter and he was half the size of the others.

She decorated the gingerbread men with care, each having socks, shirt and pants of different colors. When it came to the little gingerbread man she felt sorry for him and gave him more color than the others. ""It doesn't matter he's small,"" she thought, ""He'll still be tasty."""
</string>
    <string name="story_1_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/gingerbread/page1.jpg
</string>

    <string name="story_2_name">The Halloween House
</string>
    <string name="story_2_description">The Halloween House is big and old. I'm told that on Halloween night things happen there.
</string>
    <string name="story_2_content">"Now Suzie's moved in--she's only 4--along with her brother, her father and mother, and little Picador. He's their dog. Well, maybe half a dog. He's a Chihuahua, as small as they come.

Suzie's room is in the attic. It's no fun. With a high ceiling, cold and gloomy, and shadows that run halfway up the walls. Suzie hides under the blanket. Picador too. Come on, he's no guard dog.

Suzie's mom bought her a bear. A teddy bear named Teddy. He's big and fluffy and Suzie adores him. ""I love you so much"" she says. Then she wraps her arms around him, snuggling like a cat ready to purr while Picador buries himself in all that fur.

The Halloween House's attic may be scary, but Teddy's not. Around his neck he wears a blue scarf with red polka dots. On his back paws are black tennis shoes tied with lace and plenty of knots.

Something is silly about that teddy bear. He's got a goofy smile from ear to ear. It's kind of lopsided and sweet, although not quite complete. He was cheap when Suzie's mom bought him at the Dollar Store.

But his smile is always there.

When scratching and squeaking come from the walls,

Teddy smiles.

When clothes on the floor become strange figures in piles,

Teddy smiles.

When an invisible spider's miles of cobweb fades away in the morning,

Teddy smiles."
</string>
    <string name="story_2_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/halloween/house.jpg
</string>

    <string name="story_3_name"> Mr. Coyote Meets Mr. Snail
</string>
    <string name="story_3_description">Mr. Coyote was getting very old and had to be more careful for his own safety. He had been walking for hours and hours through a beautiful valley when he came upon a large tree. Mr. Coyote was very tired and wanted to rest but he also needed to be safe. He kindly asked the tree, "Please open up so I can rest safely in your care".
</string>
    <string name="story_3_content">"Mr. Coyote was getting very old and had to be more careful for his own safety. He had been walking for hours and hours through a beautiful valley when he came upon a large tree. Mr. Coyote was very tired and wanted to rest but he also needed to be safe. He kindly asked the tree, ""Please open up so I can rest safely in your care"".

 The tree opened up so that Mr. Coyote could go inside to rest, then it closed to keep him safe. Mr. Coyote slept for hours. When he woke up he could not remember what he had said to make the tree open. He said, ""Let me out Mr. Tree"", but nothing happened. He said, ""Please let me out now!"" and again nothing happened. The tree didn't even creak. Mr. Coyote knocked on the tree, but it would not open up. Mr. Tree was upset with Mr. Coyote for not having said please the first time he spoke to the tree! It let him rest a little longer.

Because the birds heard Mr. Coyote banging on the inside of the tree, they came down to peck on the tree to help get him out. But they were too small and the tree was just too big! Finally Mr. Woodpecker came down and pecked a hole in the tree. Although it was a very small hole, it caused Mr. Woodpecker to get a bent beak! This meant he couldn't peck on the tree any more.

Mr. Coyote put one hand out the hole but he could not fit through. He then tried his leg but still he could not fit through. He had to come up with a way to escape since Mr. Woodpecker's beak was now bent. Mr. Coyote knew there had to be a way. ""Ah, come on you old ugly tree,"" he cried, ""Just let me out!"" But still nothing happened, just the silence around him.

 Mr. Coyote decided to take off his arms one at a time and put them through the small hole. He then put his legs through one at a time by taking them off. He put his body through by taking it off. This was working out fine. I'll show you Mr. Tree, you can't keep me in here, he thought.

Next Mr. Coyote tried to put his head through the hole, but it was too big. His ears were in the way. So he took off his ears and put them through the hole. He again tried his head, but his eyes were too big. Mr. Coyote took his eyes off and put them through the hole.

 Mr. Raven saw the eyes and flew down to take them. Then Mr. Raven flew back up high in the tree with Mr. Coyote's eyes. They were such beautiful eyes, blue like the sky, and would be a treasure to put in his hiding spot!"
</string>
    <string name="story_3_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/coyote/getting_out.jpg
</string>

    <string name="story_4_name"> Absulum the Reindeer Elf
</string>
    <string name="story_4_description">"Absulum the Reindeer Elf
worked in the reindeer barn.
He had to clean it everyday
and that was rather hard
for it was such a dirty job
to mop and slop and scour and scrape
every corner, nook and cranny
in that reindeer place.
"
</string>
    <string name="story_4_content">"Absulum the Reindeer Elf
had to keep the reindeer groomed.
He had to give them all a bath.
He had to feed them too.
Cook their meals, brush their fur
and fill that barn with hay
and every morning when he woke
he would have to do it all over again.

Absulum the Reindeer Elf
played nurse and doctor too.
He took care of all the reindeer
if they were sick or had the flu.
He fixed their sleigh, he mended their reins
and if they were sad he would wipe their tears.
He worked his fingers to the bone
but it seemed that no one cared.

Of course the elves in Santa's Workshop
they were such a happy lot
singing songs all day long
with that jolly happy Santa Claus.
They laughed and danced from toy to toy
as if it was such fun
while outside in the reindeer barn
was the Elf named Absulum.

Absulum the Reindeer Elf,
when he heard that happy noise,
would wish he was a Workshop Elf
making Christmas toys;
but a Workshop Elf is wise and tall
and Absulum was not
and that was why he was in that barn,
well that is what he thought.

Now, it was on a Christmas Eve
when this incident occurred,
Santa's sleigh was flying high
there was no reason for concern
until the wind came up
and the snow came down
in a blinding wall of white
and all the reindeer say
that it set the stage
for the tragedy that took place that night.

Through that snow the reindeer flew
with neither fear nor fright
but the wind grew strong
and stronger still
until a blizzard grabbed
that Christmas night.
And it shook that night,
it shook the sky
and it shook that reindeer sleigh.
The reindeer they could hardly see
so soon they lost their way.

They were tumbling twisting
turning topsy-turvy
'round and 'round.
They hit the tree tops
flipped the sleigh
and smashed into the ground."
</string>
    <string name="story_4_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/absulum/shovel.gif
</string>

    <string name="story_5_name">Grow Your Own Gargoyle
</string>
    <string name="story_5_description">Wendy clutched her Slime Sisters comic book. She saved her allowance to buy all kinds of things that were in the back of the comic. She had bought talking fish, dancing dolls, living pet rock, giant super heroes, and all kinds of other stuff.
</string>
    <string name="story_5_content">"Wendy clutched her Slime Sisters comic book. She saved her allowance to buy all kinds of things that were in the back of the comic. She had bought talking fish, dancing dolls, living pet rock, giant super heroes, and all kinds of other stuff.

She'd run to get the mail. ""My giant super heroes are here."" Wendy had opened it up, but they weren't as big as a child like in the ad. In small print were the words ""not actual size.""

All the other things she had sent for didn't work right either. The dolls didn't have batteries and broke after just two days. The living rock was not alive, and all the other toys and games she bought were lying twisted and broken in a heap on her bed.

She sat on the floor and frowned.

""Can I come in?"" her Mom, Mrs. Delane, asked.

Wendy nodded. Mrs. Delane moved some of the junk away and sat down. She had a tiny package in her hand. ""Maybe you shouldn't send for any more toys?"" Mrs. Delane said, ""but you have one more package.""

Wendy took the package. It said ""The Living Gargoyle Co.""

""I forgot all about this,"" Wendy said. She opened the package and there were two very small gargoyles with pointy ears, and a small piece of paper.

Grow Your Own Gargoyle
Put each gargoyle in a large bowl of water. (Don't put them in the same bowl; the gargoyles need space to grow.)
Wait overnight and they will have grown more than twice their size.
Dry them off with a towel.
P.S. Gargoyles are very cranky at first, so plan activities they will enjoy like picnics and tag. No, they can't fly.

""I might as well try. I think Stacy had a sponge toy like this and hers grew."" Wendy smiled and removed the junk from her bed. ""Mom, can you get me two bowls of water?""

""If you promise to clean your room."" Her Mom said, and got her the bowls and tucked Wendy in.

Wendy went to sleep and dreamed the gargoyles grew as big as her house and were very mean looking.

She felt something wet on her ear and woke up. The gargoyles were on her bed."
</string>
    <string name="story_5_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/gargoyle/box.gif
</string>

    <string name="story_6_name">The Wumpalump
</string>
    <string name="story_6_description">"Once upon a time in the nothingness long ago... there was a Wumpalump.

 ""I am"", thought the Wumpalump. I am love, I am joy, I am peace. Nothing there is but me. ""I am"" all things…"
</string>
    <string name="story_6_content">"Once upon a time in the nothingness long ago... there was a Wumpalump.

 ""I am"", thought the Wumpalump. I am love, I am joy, I am peace. Nothing there is but me. ""I am"" all things...

 And with the Wumpalump was the Word. And the Word was the Wumpalump.

 And the Wumpalump sat and he sat and he sat. And he felt sad. ""I am"" all things he thought, but ""I am"" nothing... for no one there is to share with.

 And the sadness the Wumpalump felt grew and grew and grew. The small sorrow became a gnawing pain, a bottomless ache, a raging hunger. And when the Wumpalump could no longer bear the terrible emptiness he felt... the Word spoke.

The Wumpalump with a great deep love
gave Himself..."
</string>
    <string name="story_6_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/wumplump/wump1.gif
</string>

    <string name="story_7_name">The Loomploy
</string>
    <string name="story_7_description">"The loomploy population was divided into the able and the unable.

  The able could care for themselves in the darkness of the land. The cold did not freeze them for they were able to work hard and make warm coats."
</string>
    <string name="story_7_content">"The loomploy population was divided into the able and the unable.

  The able could care for themselves in the darkness of the land. The cold did not freeze them for they were able to work hard and make warm coats.

 The unable were sad creatures who could not help themselves. They depended upon the able to make coats for them to keep warm. This worked out fine for the able were eager to please God who had commanded:

""THOU SHALT MAKE COATS!!!!""
 It was said that heaven was a beautifully warm place filled with light. There, everything was perfect. In order to find a very tip top place in heaven one had only to make loads and loads of coats to keep the unables warm! Every able had his own visions of his wonderful place in heaven... just reward for his many coats. Except Tibley.

 Tibley didn't like to make coats. He just couldn't help himself. Everyone thought secretly that maybe Tibley really was an unable but they didn't say so out loud. Once Tibley told the head loomploy about his problem, but it didn't help much. Tibley had said, ""I just don't feel like making coats"". The head loomploy had looked at him sternly. ""You don't have to feel anything! Sometimes I feel like making coats and sometimes I don't! If I just did things when I felt like it... nothing would get done! No coats would be made and no one would get into heaven!""

 Tibley sighed. ""Oh well"", he thought, but he knew that no matter how hard he tried he couldn't make himself do something if he didn't feel like it.

 So often he would console himself and go sit amongst the unables. Of course the able loomploys thought this just punishment. One of the unables would cuddle near him. Although it could not speak, it would gently touch him now and then. Time went by and Tibley looked forward to being with the unables and his special little friend. Then one day Tibley noticed his little friend was extra quiet and no longer reached to touch him. His little friend was sick. Tibley noticed the little unable's coat had holes in it from long wear and he knew that warmth was the only thing that could bring his little friend back. So Tibley after many years became a true able. He sat down and sewed the most beautiful coat the loomploy world had ever seen. Hurriedly he put it on his little friend but nothing happened. A tear came to his eye and a great ache within him but the little friend did not move.

 Now everyone knows that when judgment day comes that the ables will go to their just reward because of their many good coats but that the unables will never get to heaven but dwell forever in the cold.

 The day came that Tibley should go to heaven. He wasn't sure if they would let him in because he had only sewed one coat his whole life. But nothing was said at the door because Kooble Loomploy who had sewed 3,000 coats in his lifetime was arguing with the Lord. ""I don't understand"", said Kooble Loomploy, ""why everyone else gets to enjoy the same amount of sunshine as me, when I sewed so many more coats! Why look at Tibley over there!! His whole 800 years he only sewed 1 coat. What kind of justice is that?"" The Lord smiled at Kooble Loomploy with sadness in his eyes. ""My Son"", he said, ""All that I have is yours!"" Kooble Loomploy was not consoled by this, but no matter, for he rushed off into the sunshine with everyone else. They danced and played and drank in the warmth and light. They were in heaven!!!"
</string>
    <string name="story_7_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/loomploy/able.jpg
</string>

    <string name="story_8_name"> Who Did Patrick's Homework?
</string>
    <string name="story_8_description">Patrick never did homework. "Too boring," he said. He played baseball and basketball and Nintendo instead. His teachers told him, "Patrick! Do your homework or you won't learn a thing." And it's true, sometimes he did feel like a ding-a-ling.
</string>
    <string name="story_8_content">"Patrick never did homework. ""Too boring,"" he said. He played baseball and basketball and Nintendo instead. His teachers told him, ""Patrick! Do your homework or you won't learn a thing."" And it's true, sometimes he did feel like a ding-a-ling.



But what could he do? He hated homework.

Then on St. Patrick's Day his cat was playing with a little doll and he grabbed it away. To his surprise it wasn't a doll at all, but a man of the tiniest size. He had a little wool shirt with old fashioned britches and a high tall hat much like a witch's. He yelled, ""Save me! Don't give me back to that cat. I'll grant you a wish, I promise you that.""

Patrick couldn't believe how lucky he was! Here was the answer to all of his problems. So he said, ""Only if you do all my homework 'til the end of the semester, that's 35 days. If you do a good enough job, I could even get A's.""

The little man's face wrinkled like a dishcloth thrown in the hamper. He kicked his legs and doubled his fists and he grimaced and scowled and pursed his lips, ""Oh, am I cursed! But I'll do it.""



And true to his word, that little elf began to do Patrick's homework. Except there was one glitch. The elf didn't always know what to do and he needed help. ""Help me! Help me!"" he'd say. And Patrick would have to help -- in whatever way.

""I don't know this word,"" the elf squeeked while reading Patrick's homework. ""Get me a dictionary. No, what's even better. Look up the word and sound it out by each letter.""

When it came to math, Patrick was out of luck. ""What are times tables?"" the elf shrieked. ""We elves never need that. And addition and subtraction and division and fractions? Here, sit down beside me, you simply must guide me.""



Elves know nothing of human history, to them it's a mystery. So the little elf, already a shouter, just got louder ""Go to the library, I need books. More and more books. And you can help me read them too.""



As a matter of fact every day in every way that little elf was a nag! Patrick was working harder than ever and was it a drag! He was staying up nights, had never felt so weary, was going to school with his eyes puffed and bleary."
</string>
    <string name="story_8_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/patrick/caught.gif
</string>

    <string name="story_9_name"> Tiger Son
</string>
    <string name="story_9_description">Once there was an elderly widow, Chen Ma, who lived with her only son inside a forest in the Shanxi Province. Her son was one of the tiger hunters licensed by the local magistrate, following the same profession of his father and grandfather before him. His share of the profits from the sale of tiger skins, meat and bones was sufficient to keep the small mud hut well provisioned for himself and his old mother.
</string>
    <string name="story_9_content">"Once there was an elderly widow, Chen Ma, who lived with her only son inside a forest in the Shanxi Province. Her son was one of the tiger hunters licensed by the local magistrate, following the same profession of his father and grandfather before him. His share of the profits from the sale of tiger skins, meat and bones was sufficient to keep the small mud hut well provisioned for himself and his old mother.

All was well until a particularly bitter winter. During a snowstorm, Chen Ma's son was separated from his fellow hunters and became food for a hungry tigress.

After her initial shock and grief subsided, Chen Ma took stock of her own utterly desperate situation -- an old woman left all alone. She went and implored the magistrate to provide her with compensation for the loss of her son, who was her only source of support. The magistrate decreed that henceforth, she would have a small share of profits from the kill of each tiger by the hunters. Needless to say, his decision was not taken well by the hunters, who had plenty of mouths of their own to feed -- both old and young."
</string>
    <string name="story_9_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/tigerson/hunters3.jpg
</string>

    <string name="story_10_name">Sliver Pete
</string>
    <string name="story_10_description">"I've never told this story before, but just the same I'm telling you now.

I was a boy of 8 in 1885 and I lived in a small town out west with my baby sister and my folks who ran the local delivery stable. It might not have been such a bad place except for one man."
</string>
    <string name="story_10_content">"I've never told this story before, but just the same I'm telling you now.

I was a boy of 8 in 1885 and I lived in a small town out west with my baby sister and my folks who ran the local delivery stable. It might not have been such a bad place except for one man.

His name was Sliver Pete and we thought him the meanest, ugliest, most cussed hombre that ever packed a gun and it was well known he carried a Colt 45. He didn't much like to work, was a cowpoke a few months out of the year and the rest of the time he played and cheated at cards and killed anybody who called him on it. Then for recreation or just pure spite he killed every sheriff that ever tried to arrest him. There wasn't a soul that didn't fear Sliver Pete, even my Father.

The townspeople ended up offering a reward of $20,000 to anyone who could either run Sliver Pete out of town or put him in his grave. Mind you, that was a fortune in those days but when Sliver Pete heard there was a price on his head he just laughed and shot up the saloon and then the bakery. He said he was worth much more money than that. And when stranger after stranger came to collect the reward they came to stay because Sliver Pete put them in the town cemetery.



One very windy day the stagecoach arrived in town with an unusual passenger. I was there to witness it because it was my duty to water the stagecoach horses. The stagecoach door swung open and a single man, tall and gaunt and dressed in a brown/black coat and hat, with a white collar, stepped out. I had seen pictures of Abraham Lincoln and that is who this man reminded me of, although I knew Abraham Lincoln would not have been wearing a preacher's clothes. He waved the coachman away as he reached for his own trunk off the roof of the coach. The trunk was wrapped in a blue cloth that flapped in the wind although partially tied with a rope. Just as he got it to the ground a gust tore at the material and I clearly saw the writing on its side. He grabbed the cloth and stuffed it back into place, glancing straight at me. Then he smiled a slow smile, winked, and put his index finger to his mouth as if to say we shared a secret. That's the only incident I saw myself and all the rest I heard secondhand through either my folks or my friends."
</string>
    <string name="story_10_thumbnail_link">http://www.magickeys.com/books/pete/buggy.gif
</string>
</resources>
